Today, we will be taking about beginning sabre fencing.
Later, I'll be talking a lot more about lunges but here I'll just give you a brief introduction.
While we know about moving like so, forward and backward, it's very important also to be able to make a lunge.
Why is a lunge important?
We're not going to want to get so close that we hit just with an advanced, we want to be able to start our attack from further away.
You remember I talked about who starts the attack first gets the point.
So, acceleration lines, I turn my arms slowly.
I begin extending them at 75% extension, the rest of my movement begins, and I've finished my extension.
My knee's above the heel.
My back leg is straight.
My back is straight.
My arms and shoulder are relaxed, not locked.
Once again, slow beginning, easy and relaxed.
Eyes forward.
Very relaxed muscles.
Don't be tense.
Don't be off balanced.
Be comfortable.